어지러운 전국 시대.
It is the turbulent Sengoku period.
카라쿠리인이 사는 지팡구국에서는 군웅할거하여 밤낮으로 접전이 계속되고
Warlords keep on fighting day and night over
the Jipangu State, where Karakuri people live.
카라쿠리 무예가들도 승리와 영광을 꿈꾸며 맹렬히 싸우고 있었다.
Karakuri Martial Artists were sharpening their swords, dreaming of victory and honor.
그리고 지금, 카라쿠리 무예자 제일을 꿈꾸는 터무니없는 영웅이 탄생했다!
And now, a wild hero has arrived, seeking to be the number one Karakuri Martial Artist!
무사시 등장이오!
Musashi enters-dasu!
카라쿠리 검호전: 무사시 로드
Karakuri Kengouden
Musashi Road
(The Story of Karakuri Martial Artist: Road of Musashi)
사내는 언제나 세계 한가운데서
A man always dreams of a day
제일 강해질 날을
in the center of the world to become
아! 아! 꿈꿔라
AH! AH! the strongest
마음의 칼을 넓은 하늘로 번쩍 쳐들어
Raise the sword of spirit high to the wide sky
모험의 길의 막을 연다
Raise the curtain to the road of adventure
지팡구국을 떠도는 검호
A skilled Martial Artist wanders Jipangu Country
그 이름은 카라쿠리인 무사시
His name is Musashi, a Karakuri Man
격렬한 칼의 소리가
Intense clash of swords
눈부신 인생
makes a life dazzle
싸웠던 어제보다도 오늘 강해진다
Fight yesterday and become stronger today
무예! 이도류 무사시
Martial Art! Dual Blade is Musashi
내일은 빛난다
Tomorrow will be glorious
격렬한 칼의 소리가
Intense clash of swords
눈부신 인생
makes a life dazzle
싸우는 한껏 고요함과 함께
Fight the utmost with the tranquility
무예! 이도류 무사시
Martial Art! Dual Blade is Musashi
미간이 빛나고 있었다 무사시!!
The brow was shining! Musashi!!
여행하며 동쪽으로 갔던 무사시는 시미즈 항에서 이시마츠하고 만난다.
While Musashi was heading to the east, he met Ishimatsu in Shimizu harbor.
무사시하고 닮은 그 성격에 둘의 우정이 뜨겁게 불타오른다.
Their friendship burns up by his personality that's similar with Musashi's.
그러나 전투 후 결국, 이시마츠는 베어져 죽고 말았다.
But after the fight, Ishimatsu was cut to death.
슬픔에 잠겼던 무사시는 에도토피아를 향한다.
Musashi is in deep grief, but he still heads to Edotopia.
꽃도 바람도 에도토피아이오
Flower and Storm at Edotopia
아, 드디어 도착했소. 이것이 애태우던 에도토피아...
I finally am here-dasu. This is the Edotopia that I admired-dasu!
무사시는 내일부터 시작하는 지팡구 무예 대회에 향해 열렬한 투지를 불태우고 있었다.
Musashi was burning with the fighting spirit for Jipangu Martial Arts Competition that starts tomorrow.
오츠루, 보고 계시오! 꼭 나는 지팡구 제일의 무예가가 되어 보이겠소!
Otsuru is looking at me-dasu! I will definitely become the number one Martial Artist of Jipangu-dasu!
배가 고프오...
I am hungry-dasu...
오츠루... 나, 오츠루가 만든 주먹밥이 먹고 싶소...
Otsuru... I want to eat the rice balls made by you-dasu...
멈춰라!
Stop!
Stop right there!
무, 무슨 일이오? 쫒기고 있는 자는 아름다운 여자오.
Wh- what's going on-dasu? A beautiful girl is being chased-dasu.
멈추랬다!
I told you to stop!
자, 각오해라.
Now, prepare yourself.
연약한 여자를 괴롭히는 것은 용서할 수 없소!
It is unforgivable to bully a tender girl-dasu!
이제 괜찮소. 나머지는 내게 맡기시오.
It's all right now-dasu. Leave the rest to me-dasu.
감사합니다.
Thank you so much.
뭐, 뭐냐, 너! 방해하면 용서하지 않겠다!
Wh- what are you doing?! I won't forgive you if you get in my way!
무서워!
I'm scared!
무, 무슨 소리오! 당신은 나쁜 사람이오!
Wh- what are you talking about-dasu?! You're a bad guy-dasu!
멍청한 소리 마라! 내가 눈에 들어오지 않냐!
Don't say stupid! Don't you see who I am?!
그런 큰 게 들어올 리가 없소!
Of course I do! You are a man-dasu!
그런 게 아냐! 이 짓떼는 저 여자를 책임지고 잡을 수 있다는 증거다!
That's not it! This truncheon is the proof that I can catch that woman responsibly!
그러니까 무슨 소리오!
I still don't get what you're talking about-dasu!
멍청한 자식이군! 알았어? 이 여자는 말이다!
You're one stupid guy! You know who this girl is?!
지금 에도토피아를 떠들썩하게 만드는 도적의 동료다!
She works for the thiefs that are disturbing Edotopia!
저, 정말이오?
Re- really-dasu?
아닙니다.
It's not true.
자, 보시오! 대체 이런 아름다운 아가씨가 악행을 할 리가 없소!
See! There is no way such pretty girl would do such bad things-dasu!
안 되겠어, 얘.
This guy is no good.
에이, 성가시다! 너도 같이 잡혀버려라!
You're annoying! I'll catch you too!
자, 어떠냐.
How's that?
흥, 정의는 언제나 이기오!
Hmph, justice always wins-dasu!
젠장! 너 두고 보자!
Dammit! You're gonna pay for this!
얘야, 정말 고맙다.
Thank you, kid.
난 얘가 아니오. 난 지팡구 제일의 무예가를 꿈꾸는 미야모토 마을의 무사시오.
I am not a kid-dasu. I am Musashi from Miyamoto village who will be the number one Martial Artist of Jipangu-dasu.
무사시 군, 강한 인상의 이름이네.
Musashi? That is a name with strong feeling.
이야, 부끄럽소.
You make me shy-dasu.
그건 그렇고 무사시 군, 네 힘을 빌려 도와줬으면 하는 게 있어.
Anyway, Musashi, I have something that I want you to help.
나, 아가씨를 위해서라면 무엇이라도 하겠소!
I will do anything for a young lady-dasu!
그래도...
Still...
그래도?
Still?
나, 배가 비었소.
I am so hungry-dasu.
저런.
Oh.
그렇게 해서 배가 찰 만큼 국수를 실컷 먹은 무사시는 아카네라는 여자의 부탁을 듣게 되었다.
Therefore, Musashi is going to do as a girl named Akane said, after eating noodles as much as he wanted.
오늘 하루만 밤에 혹시 모르니 아까의 jutte를 가진 사람들로부터 우리 가족을 지켜줬으면 좋겠어.
I'd like if you protected my family from those people with [jutte] you saw before.
라고 했다.
And that's what she said.
그럼 무사시 군, 잘 부탁해.
Then, Musashi, I entrust you.
배가 가득 찼더니 졸려졌소...
Now I'm full, so I got sleepy-dasu...
돈은 어디 있나.
Show me the money.
오, 사건 발생이다! 전원 대흑야에 급히 나가라!
We got a situation! Everyone, hurry up to Daigokuya!
예!
Right!
제니가탄
Zenigatan
아카네 씨 목소리다...
Ms. Akane's voice...
아카네 씨!
Ms. Akane!
자! 곧장 죄인을 묶어라!
Now! Tie up the criminal right away!
더 이상 용서는 없다!
We won't forgive you anymore!
잠깐! 기다리시오!
Stop! Wait! Wait for me-dasu!
또 녀석들의 동료이오? 끈질긴 패거리오!
Those bastards' comrades again-dasu? How persistent-dasu!
무사시 군!
Musashi!
지금이오! 아카네 씨 달아나시오!
Now! Ms. Akane, run away-dasu!
네!
Right!
멈춰라! 어이!
Stop! Hey!
그렇게는 못하오!
You won't do that-dasu!
에잇, 방해되는 놈! 잡아라!
You're in the way! Get him!
주제넘는!
What impertinence!
뭐, 뭣이오?
Wh- what're you doing-dasu?!
제니가탄! 양문 던지기!
Zenigatan! High Grade Coin Throw!
돈을 던지면 안 되오!
You shouldn't throw money-dasu!
흥! 곧잘 채워질 테니까 괜찮다!
Hmph! I earn more than these!
끝장이다!
Finish!
4문 초대형이다!
4 mon coin supersized!
잡았다!
Got you!
좋아, 지금이다! 총공격!
Good! Everyone, go get him!
참 세상 물정 모르는 멍청한 놈이군.
What an ignorant about the world.
그래도 날 아가씨라고 불러줬어! 너하고는 달라.
But still, he called me miss! He's different from you.
멍청아! 뭘 불평하냐!
You idiot! What are you complaining about?
봉행소
Magistrate's Office
고문중
Torturing
어떠냐, 무사시! 이래도 자백하지 않을 텐가!
How's that, Musashi?! Aren't you going to admit yet?
아니오! 난 도둑 따위의 동료가 아니오!
No! I am not a friend of such thieves-dasu!
그럼 날 물에 빠뜨린 건 어디 누가!
Then, who from where knocked me into water?!
그러니까 난 짓떼가 정의의 증표였다는 것을 몰랐소!
I didn't know that truncheon was a sign of justice!
둘러댈 생각 마라!
Do not make excuses!
그러니까 우리 마을에는 그런 걸 가진 인간 따위는 없었소!
Again, there was nobody with such thing in my village-dasu!
그럼 또 한번 묻겠다. 왜 넌 그 여자에게 속았나?
Then I'll ask you again. Why were you fooled by such woman?
아니오, 아니오! 아카네 씨는 절대 나쁜 사람이 아니오!
No, no! Ms. Akana cannot be a bad person-dasu!
에잇, 아직도 정신 못 차렸냐!
Damn, stop being irresponsible!
지팡 무예대회 회장
Jipangu
Martial
Arts
Competition
Site
무사시! 지팡 제일!
Musashi! The best of Jipangu!
무사시 씨! 힘내요!
Mr. Musashi, do your best!
그럼 이제 지팡구 제일을 정하는 무예 대회 결승전을 시작합니다.
The decisive match of the number one of Jipangu starts right now.
코지로, 깨지시오!
Kojirou, be broken!
뭐라?!
What?!
네이놈!
You punk!
무사시... 강해졌구나...
Musashi... you've become strong.
무사시 씨 대단해! 멋져요!
Mr. Musashi, you're awesome! So cool!
무사시 씨! 빨리 결혼해요!
Mr. Musashi! Let's marry right away!
이놈, 기절한 주제에 웃고 있어!
This brat is laughing in coma!
끈덕진 놈이군! 감방에 넣어라!
He sure is stubborn! Throw him into jail!
신입이다. 사이좋게 살아라.
He's new. Get along.
죽은 거 아냐?
Is he dead?
아니, 살아있긴 한 거 같아.
Well, he at least looks alive.
과연 무사시는 무예 대회에 나갈 수 있을까? 질풍노도의 후반을 기다려라!
Can Musashi go out to the martial arts competition? Wait for the stormy latter half!
카라쿠리 검호전 무사시 로드
Karakuri Kengouden: Musashi Road
by Subdivers
어라? 하늘에 불꽃이 오르는 걸 보니, 오늘 행사 있나?
Huh? To see the fireworks on the sky... Is there an event today?
제 1회 무예대회가 오늘부터 시작해.
The first competition starts as of today.
그래, 무예대회구나.
I see, that's the martial arts competition.
저 불꽃은!
That fireworks!
야, 얘야, 뭘 화들짝 놀라서 그러냐.
Hey, kiddo, what are you so surprised about?
아, 아저씨! 저거 무예대회 불꽃이오?
Uh, uncle! Is that the fireworks from the martial arts competition-dasu?
어, 그래.
That's right.
오 마이 갓!
Oh my god!
꺼내 주시오! 여기에서! 아무도 없소?!
Get me out of here! Isn't there anybody around-dasu?!
꺼내 주시오! 젠장!
Get me out-dasu! Damn!
얘야, 조용히 해라!
Kiddo, be quiet!
이게 조용히 할 수 있어 보이오?!
Do you think I can be quiet-dasu?!
오늘만은 얼마나 날뛰어도 아무도 안 들어.
For today, nobody will listen to you no matter how you yell.
왜오?
Why-dasu?
여기 놈들은 모두 무예대회의 경비로 갔으니까.
Everyone here went as guards to the martial arts competition.
그럼 나 어떻게 되는 것이오!
Than what happens to me-dasu?!
얌전히 여기 있는 거지.
Be obedient and be here.
말도 안 되오! 내가 무예 대회에 나가기 위해 에도토피아에 왔소!
No way-dasu! I came to Edotopia to go out to the martial arts competition!
좋아, 그럼 저곳으로!
Then I'll use that way!
여기, 에도 성에서는 바로 지팡구 무예 대회의 접수가 시작됐다.
Here, in Edo Castle, the reception for Jipangu Martial Arts Competition has begun.
돌격류 야마도나 우에이오.
Rush style, Yamadona Ue.
야마도나 우에.
Yamadona Ue.
제 6회장에 가세요.
Go to sixth grounds.
반류, 미스터 코지로.
Reversal style, Mister Kojirou.
야규 신영류, 쥬베.
Yagyuu Shinkage style, Jube.
쿠사리가마류 바이켄! 출전하오!
Kusarigama style, Baiken! I participate!
나는 우시와카라 하오.
You may call me Ushiwaka.
벤케이라 하오.
I am Benkei!
제 1회 지팡구 무예 대회의 규칙에 따라 대회 참가 신청은 오늘 오후 6시 종이 울릴 때까지.
According to the rules of the first Jipangu Martial Arts Competition, we will accept entries until 6'o clock bell.
또, 참가인 다수를 위해 신청 후 즉시 각 예선장에서 시합을 하겠다.
Also, for the majority of participants, as soon as you register, you'll have a match in respective preliminary place.
지팡구 무예 대회에서는 우선 7개의 회장으로 이루어져 예선을 치룬다.
In Jipangu Martial Arts Competition, people enter preliminary contest in seven different places.
제3예선회장
3rd preliminary place
무도장
Place of Match
동! 호리고시 류 오의를 전수받은 주자부로!
East! Full mastership of Horigoshi style, Juuzaburo!
서! 반류 미스터 코지로!
West! Reversal style Mister Kojirou!
미스터 코지로의 승리!
Mister Kojirou wins!
스승님, 저 분은 언젠가 우리 마을에 온 적이...
Master, I remember that person passing through our village.
저 남자 분명 최후까지 남을 거야.
That man will survive to the end.
무사시 씨는 어디에 있을까요?
I wonder where is Mr. Musashi...
다른 예선장에 있겠지.
He should be in another place.
다른 곳을 알아보자.
Let's find in somewhere else.
네.
Yes.
호외! 호외! 빨리도 우승 후보가 나타났습니다!
Extra! Extra! A champion candidate has already appeared!
어? 뭐야, 뭐야?
Huh? What's this?
지팡구 무예 대회에서 강력한 우승 후보 나타나다.
A strong champion candidate appears in Jipangu Martial Arts Competition?
그 이름은 반류 미스터 코지로.
His name is Banryu Mister Kojirou.
코지로?!
Kojirou?
정말이오?!
Are you serious-dasu?!
바보 놈.
Idiot.
왜이오! 왜 나 혼자 이런 꼴에 처한 것이오!
Why-dasu! Why must only I suffer this-dasu!
난 절대 나쁜 일을 한 적이 없소!
I never did something wrong-dasu!
난 이제 무엇도 믿지 않겠소...
I won't trust anything from now on-dasu...
신도 저주하겠소.
I will curse the god too-dasu.
제니가탄 두목, 이 얘는 무고혀, 분명.
Boss Zenigatan, this kid is definitely innocent.
이런 순수한 놈이 거짓말을 할 리가 없어.
There is no way such pure guy would lie!
당신도 무고한 자에게 죄를 지우면 찝찝해지지 않겠는가?
Wouldn't you feel uneasy if you charge someone innocent?
게다가 이 사건의 진범인을 잡는다면 큰손을 잡을 수 있지 않겠어?
Moreover, if you find out the real criminal of this incident, wouldn't it lead to the finding of the behind boss?
맞는 말이군.
That's right.
누군가에 따르면, 현장 100번. 에도 옛날부터 증거가 없을 때에는
According to someone, 100 times to the scene. Long before Edo period, they say one should return to
현장으로 돌아가 생각해 보라고 했다.
the scene and think again when there's not enough evidences.
어이, 너도 빨리 뭔가 단서가 될 만할 걸 기억해내 봐라.
Hey, you'd better remember something that will work as a clue.
그, 그게... 배가 고파서 머리가 잘 안 돌아가지 않소...
Th- that is... I'm too hungry to use my head-dasu...
어쩔 수 없는 놈이군.
What an useless guy...
국수 한 그릇 더!
One bowl more, please!
네, 나왔습니다!
Here you go!
거참, 네 속은 어떻게 되먹었냐?
Huh, is there a hungry monster in your stomach or what?
이렇게 먹어 미안하오. 돈 있소?
I'm sorry for eating this much-dasu. Do you have money-dasu?
그럼, 동전이라면 잔뜩 있지.
Of course, I have lots of coins.
기억났소.
I remembered.
응?
Hm?
그래도 정말 무사시 군 위장 한번 대단하네!
But really, Musashi, your stomach is terrific!
나도 국수가 제일 좋으니까 매일 양국집 국수를 먹으러 오는데.
Since I like noodles so much, I come to eat noodles in Ryoumokuya.
너같은 사람은 본 적 없어.
But I never saw someone like you.
양국집 국수.
Ryoumokuya's noodles.
양국집.
Ryoumokuya.
왜 빨리 기억해내지 못했냐!
Why didn't you remember that earlier?!
그래도 아카네 씨는 절대 나쁜 사람이 아니오!
But Ms. Akane is definitely not a bad person-dasu!
에이, 아직도 그런 소리를!
Hmph, forget it!
호외! 호외!
Extra! Extra!
또 대단한 무예가가 나타났습니다! 그 자는 바로 바이켄이에요!
An awesome Martial Artist has appeared again! The name is Baiken!
바이켄...
Baiken...
그래!
Oh, right!
갑자기 멈추지 마라!
Don't stop so suddenly!
잊어먹었다! 빨리 신청하러 가오!
I forgot! I must go enter-dasu!
안 돼. 아직 네 결백함이 정해진 게 아냐!
Not yet. You are not proven innocent yet!
그보다 빨리 이거나 제대로 해!
First, do this properly right now!
그래도... 마감이...
But... the deadline!
괜찮다.
It's all right.
저녁 6시까진 아직 시간이 있어!
There is still some time until 6'o clock!
봐! 찾던 국수집!
Look! The noodle house we were looking for!
저쪽이다!
There it is!
어이, 귀재! 포기해라!
Hey, genius! Surrender!
뭔 짓이야!
What are you doing?!
뭔 짓이야! 등에 상처날 뻔했잖아!
What was that for?! You almost hurt me in my back!
잔소리 많은 여자군!
You're a woman with all talk!
자! 나머지 동료는 어디 있냐! 솔직히 뱉어내라! 뱉어내지 않으면 아프게 될 테다!
Now, tell me where your friends are! Spit it out! Or else, it's gonna be hurt!
자, 자, 자!
Now, now, now!
왜 그러냐!
What's holding you up?
무사시 군!
Musashi!
이제 괜찮소.
It's all right now-dasu.
뭔 짓이냐!
What the heck are you doing?!
아카네 씨는 아무것도 하지 않았소!
Ms. Akana didn't do anything-dasu!
뭐냐, 또 너! 멍청한 소리 마라!
Is it you again? Don't be stupid!
작작 좀 해라!
Can't you behave?!
당신이야말로 어딜 눈여겨 보는 것이오!
Who are you suspecting at-dasu?!
아카네 씨는 배가 고팠을 때 곧 죽었을 것만 같은 나에게 배가 가득 차도록 국수를 먹게 해 주었소!
Ms. Akane let me eat noodles until I was totally full, when I was starving to death-dasu!
이런 마음고운 사람이 나쁜 일을 할 리가 없소!
There is no way such kind person would do bad things-dasu!
누가 뭐래도 당신이... 아카네 씨를 잡는다고 하면 난 목숨을 걸어서라도 지키겠소!
Whatever you say, if you're going to get Ms. Akane, I'll protect him risking my life-dasu!
무사시! 공무집행방해로 체포한다!
Musashi! I'm arresting you for obstruction of justice!
바라던 바오.
That's what I wanted-dasu.
돈을 다 쓰셨소!
I guess you used all the money-dasu!
안타깝군. 아직 있다!
Sorry, but I still have some!
빅 코인! 4문 초대형!
Big coin!4 mon coin supersized!
칫, 의자로 막은 덕에 조금 방향이 어긋났구나.
Hmph, that chair made me miss the target.
목숨은 건졌군, 무사시!
Consider yourself lucky, Musashi!
방심하셨소!
Guards down-dasu?
아카네 씨! 이 틈이오! 빨리 달아나시오!
Ms. Akane! Now-dasu! Hurry up and run away-dasu!
그, 그래도... 무사시 군은...
B- but... what about you?
나, 나는 신경쓰지 마시오. 빨리 달아나시오!
I- I'll be all right-dasu. Just run away-dasu!
어떻소! 이래도 아직 아카네 씨를 범인이라 할 것이오?
How's this? Are you still going to accuse Ms. Akane as criminal-dasu?
무사시 군, 이제 그만둬.
Musashi, you can stop now.
졌어.
I lost.
미안해. 사실 나는 제니가탄 두목이 말한 대로 도둑의 동료야.
Sorry. Actually, I work for the thieves just as Boss Zenigatan said.
기뻤어. 날 이렇게까지 믿어 준 건 무사시 군 뿐이야.
I was happy. Only Musashi trusted me this much.
아카네 씨...
Ms. Akane...
안 돼! 무사시! 저건 여섯 시를 알리는 종이야.
No! Musashi! That's the 6'o clock bell!
빨리 성으로 서둘러!
Hurry up to the castle!
자, 무사시 군! 어서 가.
Now, Musashi! Go for it!
아카네 씨. 다시 또 국수를 같이 먹으오!
Ms. Akane! Let's have noodles together again-dasu!
기다려 주시오!
Wait for me-dasu!
곧장 사람을 믿은 무사시는 사람의 마음을 바꾸었다.
After trusting a person single-mindedly, Musashi managed to change a person.
그러나 지팡구 제일을 꿈꾸는 무사시는 무예 대회 접수에 아쉽게 참여하지 못했다.
But sadly for Musashi who wanted to be the number one Martial Artist of Jipangu, he didn't managed to the reception.
무사시 앞에 기다리고 있는 것은 비인가, 폭풍인가, 태풍인가?
What is waiting in front of Musashi? A rain, a storm, or a typhoon?
허공의 주머니에 달이
Sometimes the moon jumps over
뛰어넘어가는 일도 있어
the pocket of the empty sky
큰 소리로 웃으면
Laugh loudly and
내일에는 아침이 와
a morning will come tomorrow
잃는 것 따위는 아무것도 아니야
Don't care too much about losing
계속 해나가! 앞으로 가!
Keep doing! Go for it!
맨손은 강해
A bare hand is strong
그런 거야! 가볍게 가자
That's how it is! Let's go lightly
인생 그런 거야! 기회가 어라,
That's how life is! Look, a chance
꼬리를 흔들며 쫒아와!
follows us wagging its tail!
그런 거야! 가볍게 가자
That's how it is! Let's go lightly
미래도 그런 거야! 내일이 어라,
That's how future also is! Look, tomorrow
양손을 벌리고 웃고 있어!
is opening its hands and smiling at us!
무예 대회의 참가 접수를 아쉽게 놓쳐 난 출전할 수 없게 되어버렸소.
Because I couldn't make it to the reception for the martial arts competition, I can't participate-dasu.
분하오! 대회장 탈의실에 숨어들어 몰래 출전할 수 있게 되었소만
So frustrating! I sneaked into a locker room and got to go out for the competition-dasu.
역시 나쁜 일은 안 되오...
But after all I guess I can't do bad things-dasu...
정체가 밝혀져 거듭 관리들에게 쫒기는 신세에 처하고 말았소.
Now that my true identity is revealed, I am now being pursued by officials-dasu.
다음 이야기! 난입 무예대회
Next story! Raid into the Martial Arts Competition
질풍노도의 대활약을 보시오!
Check out the stormy great activity!
다음 이야기
난입! 무예대회
재미있게 보세요!
Next Story
Raid into
the Martial Arts Competition
We hope you enjoy!